<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Alex Norell</title><link>https://alexnorell.com/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Alex Norell</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 09:57:26 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alexnorell.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Startup Infrastructure Design</title><link>https://alexnorell.com/post/startup-infrastructure-design/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 09:57:26 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://alexnorell.com/post/startup-infrastructure-design/</guid><description>A company asked me to design their infrastructure as part of an interview. This seems like free work, but hey, it makes a good post and is a fun exercise.
Prompt As we scale, we need to streamline our code deployment and infrastructure to be as efficient and robust as possible so that we can iterate quickly. These are some of the challenges that you’d be solving.
Problem What tools/processes do you use for cloud infrastructure management, security, and auditing?</description></item><item><title>IoT Village Virtual CTF</title><link>https://alexnorell.com/post/iotvillage-virtual-ctf-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 10:31:33 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://alexnorell.com/post/iotvillage-virtual-ctf-2021/</guid><description>Last week, IoTVillage hosted a virtual Capture the Flag (CTF) event. The purpose of the event is to use known exploits on devices to retrieve information from within the device. This information is known as a flag and can really be anything; from the MD5 of a particular function, to the contents of a file in the system.
The CTF is set up as a 3 tiered network with vulnerable devices in each network.</description></item><item><title>State of the Desk 2021</title><link>https://alexnorell.com/post/desk-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 15:19:45 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alexnorell.com/post/desk-2021/</guid><description>An overview of my home office desk.</description></item><item><title>Add Cloudfront to a Website</title><link>https://alexnorell.com/post/add-cloudfront-to-website/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://alexnorell.com/post/add-cloudfront-to-website/</guid><description>The domain I&amp;rsquo;m using, norell.dev, requires the site to be served via HTTPS, or else the browser won&amp;rsquo;t display it. Google, the owners of the gTLD, requires HSTS for the domain.
From the get.dev page:
Your security is our priority. The .dev top-level domain is included on the HSTS preload list, making HTTPS required on all connections to .dev websites and pages without needing individual HSTS registration or configuration. Security is built in.</description></item><item><title>Add External Domain in AWS and create record for S3</title><link>https://alexnorell.com/post/add-external-domain-aws/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 21:21:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://alexnorell.com/post/add-external-domain-aws/</guid><description>I have a domain name, norell.dev that is regeisterd outside of AWS. I would like to use it for my development within AWS, but Amazon doesn&amp;rsquo;t support the .dev domain name. Google is the gTLD owner, and Amazon and Google don&amp;rsquo;t play well together. Even though Amazon won&amp;rsquo;t let me transfer my domain to be registered in Route53, I can still configure it to be used using Hosted Zones.
I will follow this guide to get it set up.</description></item><item><title>Host Website in AWS S3</title><link>https://alexnorell.com/post/host-website-in-aws/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 23:06:28 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://alexnorell.com/post/host-website-in-aws/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m want to deploy a copy of this website to AWS S3, and set up all of the necessary infrastructure using terraform. This post will go over the steps that were taken to achieve this.
Set up provider This will be using AWS, so the terraform provider must be set. This will use the latest terraform version, 0.13.
The provider is defined below, and located in main.tf
provider &amp;#34;aws&amp;#34; { version = &amp;#34;~&amp;gt; 3.</description></item><item><title>Switching to Netlify for static hosting</title><link>https://alexnorell.com/post/switching-to-netlify/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 12:59:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://alexnorell.com/post/switching-to-netlify/</guid><description>Previously I had my website hosted in a GCP instance behind nginx. That really was too much overhead for what I actually needed for this site.
A couple of the downsides:
Manual setup of the entire GCP instance No CI pipeline No CDN Expensive Manual Set Up I go over in my previous post, Creating and Deploying This Website. In summary, I was previously using the free tier of GCP to host a nano sized instance that contained nGINX and several static websites.</description></item><item><title>Creating and Deploying This Website</title><link>https://alexnorell.com/post/creating-and-deploying-this-website/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alexnorell.com/post/creating-and-deploying-this-website/</guid><description>A detailed explanation on how this website is generated and hosted.</description></item></channel></rss>